James Symons-Hicks

J +447522555117

in LinkedIn

in LinkedIn

Profile

Highly motivated UCL MSc Economics student with a strong research background. I have a strong passion for applying analytical insights to real-world challenges and a range of technical and programming skills. My research interests include macroeconomics, financial economics, behavioural economics, and experimental economics.

Education

University College London

Sep 2023 – Sep 2024*
Grade: In Progress

MSc Economics

Grade

Core Modules: Microeconomics, Macroeconomics, Econometrics, Research Methods, Dissertation.

Optional Modules: Advanced Macroeconomic Theory, Advanced Microeconometrics, Machine Learning in Economics, Topics in Money and Finance.

Modules Audited: Advanced Microeconomic Theory, Time Series Econometrics.

University College London BSc Economics Sep 2020 – Jun 2023

Grade: First Class Honours

Selected Coursework: Microeconomics (76%), Economics of Finance (78%), Advanced Economics of Finance (72%), Spanish L6 (76%), Macroeconomic Theory & Policy (72%).

<u>Dissertation</u>: "Unravelling the Influence of Retail Investors on Liquidity and Volatility in UK Markets" (74%)

St. David's Sixth Form College, Cardiff

Sep 2018 – Jul 2020

Grade: A *A *A *A *

 $A-Levels\ -\ Economics,\ Mathematics,\ Spanish,\ Media\ Studies.$

Awards: Academic Excellence - Economics & Media Studies. Outstanding Studentship - Spanish.

Technical Skills

Languages: English (Native), Spanish (Advanced).

Other: Microsoft Excel (proficient), Level 3 Emergency First Aid at Work, LTA Level 2 Tennis Coach.

Academic Positions

Pre-Doctoral Research Assistant

September 2024 – Present

 $Centre\ for\ Macroeconomics,\ London\ School\ of\ Economics$

• Working with Prof. Matthias Doepke and Dr. Ethan Ilzetzki.

Research Assistant May 2022 – September 2024

Prof. Antonio Guarino, University College London

London, UK

London, UK

- Working across multiple projects relating to financial decision-making and experimental economics.
- Assisted with interactive, computer-based laboratory experiments of undergraduate students and professional traders.
- Developed MATLAB programmes to analyse experimental data using Maximum Likelihood Estimation.
- Utilised Python to clean experimental data, create graphics, and conduct hypothesis testing.
- Editing and proofreading academic articles for publication.
- Creating and editing conference presentation slides, including creating graphics and visuals.

Research & Publications

The Influence of Market Dynamics on Retail Investor Attention | Link

Oct 2023

• Published in UCL Journal of Economics 2023.

Impacts of the EU Referendum Decision on the Welsh Economy | Link

Jun 2022

• Shortlisted for UCL's Explore Econ Conference 2022.

Economics with Humans: The Importance of Behavioural Economics | Link

Jan 2022

• Blog article for The Economic Tribune.

Other Research Experience

Peer Reviewer, UCL Journal of Economics	2024
Student Research Fellow, UCL Economic Tribune	Oct 2022 – Jul 2023
Presenter & Panel Discussion Member, Discover Economics Project	June 2023
Scientific Committee, UCL Explore Econ Conference	June 2023

Other Work Experience

The Access to Sport Project $Tennis\ Coach$

Nov~2021-Aug~2022

London, UK

- Delivered free/low-cost tennis sessions to children and adults, including 30+ players school groups and summer holiday camps.
- Supported 5 volunteers/junior coaches in qualification progressions by providing on-court feedback during lessons.
- Undertook additional training sessions to teach players with additional learning needs.

Extra-Curricular

Captain of UCL Tennis Men's 3, Member of UCL Economist's Society, Member of UCL Snowsports.